The holiest event of our time. Perfect for their return.
Angels & Demons is a thriller, mystery film directed by Ron Howard.
Harvard symbologist Robert Langdon is recruited by the Vatican to investigate the apparent return of the Illuminati – a
secret, underground organization – after four cardinals are kidnapped on the night of the papal conclave.
Robert Langdon, played by Tom Hanks.
Camerlengo Patrick McKenna, played by Ewan McGregor.
Vittoria Vetra, played by Ayelet Zurer.
Commander Richter, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Inspector Olivetti, played by Pierfrancesco Favino.
Assassin, played by Nikolaj Lie Kaas.
Angels & Demons is a 2009 American mystery thriller film directed by Ron
Howard and written by Akiva Goldsman and David Koepp.
It is based on Dan Brown's 2000 novel of the same title.
A prequel to the 2006 film The Da Vinci Code, also directed by Howard, it is the second installment in the
Robert Langdon film series; however, the novel version was published before The Da Vinci Code novel.
Filming took place in Rome, Italy, and the Sony
Pictures Studios in Culver City, California.
Tom Hanks reprises his role as Professor Robert
Langdon, while Ayelet Zurer stars as Dr.
Vittoria Vetra, a CERN scientist joining Langdon in the quest to recover a
missing vial of antimatter from a mysterious Illuminati terrorist.
Producer Brian Grazer, composer Hans Zimmer and screenwriter Akiva Goldsman
also return, with Koepp coming on board to help the latter.
Angels and Demons premiered in Rome on May 4, 2009, and was released on May 15,
by Sony Pictures Releasing through the Columbia Pictures banner.
It grossed $485.9 million worldwide against a $150 million production budget, becoming the ninth highest-grossing film
of 2009, and received mixed reviews from critics, who considered it an improvement over its predecessor.
A sequel, titled Inferno, concluded the series in 2016.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, rome,
italy, vatican (holy see), symbolism, illuminati.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.